A Guide to the Papers of Mark Twain, 1862-1946
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series II: Letters
  - Mark Twain to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1900 August 18; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Declines offer because of family's day of mourning for Susy. With AN on envelope inviting MacAlister to visit. S.L.C.] (w/env) (mourning stationery)
  - [Mark Twain to Frank Fuller], [1900 August]; AN, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Requests him to check spelling on ship names. No signature.] (w/mourning env)
  - Mark Twain, London, to [W. H.] Helm, 1900 September 17; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Thanks for a complimentary review he had written; packing for move back to America; compares removals and funerals and is tired of attending them. S.L.C.] (mourning stationery)
  - Mark Twain to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1900 September 19; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Cannot write for Lloyds Christmas number because his contracts debar him; wants the MacAlisters to visit them; discusses an aphorism on intolerance. M.T.] (w/env) (mourning stationery)
  - Mark Twain to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1900 September 24; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Invites him and family for dinner Monday as the Clemenses are moving; asks him to safe-guard a play and typed manuscript; wants MacAlister to represent him in some financial matters. S.L.C.] (w/env) (mourning stationery)
  - Mark Twain to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1900 September 26; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Asks MacAlister to represent him in some financial matters; will be sailing for America October 6. S.L.C.] (w/env) (mourning stationery)
  - Mark Twain to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1900 September 27; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Says he is using all his influence with God on MacAlister's behalf. M.T.] (w/env)
  - [Mark Twain to John Young Walker MacAlister], [1900 September]; AL (photocopy), 3 p. (Box 5)
    Discusses London hotels with humorous specific complaints and exaggeration; plans to sail on "The Minnehaha" on Saturday.
  - Olivia L. Clemens, S.S. Minnehaha, to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1900 October 6; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Says goodbye with warm thanks and good wishes to the MacAlisters.] (w/env)
  - Mark Twain to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1900 October 16; ALS, 3 p. (Box 5)
    Reports no seasickness except for the maid, whom they treated with Plasmon; notes that Plasmon given to ill patient by ship's surgeon; discusses Plasmon business. M.T.] (w/env)
  - Mark Twain, Hotel Earlington, New York, to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1900 October 27; ALS, 4 p. (Box 5)
    Discusses the Plasmon company in America and in England; says Henry H. Rogers agrees with him; says Dr. Cook very capable; thinks they have a furnished house for a year. M.T.] (w/env)
  - Mark Twain, New York, to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1900 [October 31]; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Asks for London and Berlin reports; says Plasmon factory will be on famous Briar Cliff dairy farm. Written on printed testimonial for Plasmon. M.T.
  - Mark Twain to [William W.] Ellsworth, [1900] November 2; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Agrees to December 4 for Aldine [Club], with no reporters present. S.L.C.] (mourning stationery)
  - John Townsend Trowbridge, Arlington, MA, to Society of American Authors, 1900 November 14; ALS, 3 p. (Box 5)
    Regrets he will be unable to attend "festival" and pay tribute to Mark Twain; praises Twain highly.
  - President, Harper & Brothers, New York, to Mark Twain, 1900 November 14; TL (copy), 1 p. (Box 5)
    Confirms verbal agreements of exclusive serial rights to Twain's articles and exclusive publishing rights to any books for a one year period and details of royalty payments and advertising agreements until January 1 1902.
  - William Gillette, Baltimore, to Mark Twain with ALS [1900] November 16 Mark Twain to Henry H. Rogers, 1900 November 15; ALS, 3 p. (Box 5)
    Discusses royalty payments for a dramatization of Adventures of Tom Sawyer as suggested by [Charles] Frohman; offer comparable to Richard Carvell agreement; fee would be split between Twain and dramatizer; has suggested Twain get a percentage of gross receipts. On verso, ALS [1900] November 16 Mark Twain to Henry H. Rogers asks him to look over offer, says he will sign it, and questions possibility of time limit on Adventures of Tom Sawyer dramatization but not on Adventures of Huckleberry Finn dramatization. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, New York, to Poultney Bigelow, New York, 1900 November 20; APCS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    In German. Hears he is home already; asks if it is suitable to visit right away. M.T.
  - Mark Twain to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1900 December 5; ALS, 4 p. (Box 5)
    Apologizes for ignoring registered letter; discusses Plasmon and its financing; says he has been sick in bed; will be giving his last lecture for the season on December. 12. M.T.] (w/env)
  - Mark Twain to Irving Bacheller, 1900 December 14; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Thanks him very much for book; says he has replied to thirty-eight other letters today and this is the first one he has enjoyed writing. M.T.] (morning stationery)
  - Mark Twain, New York, to [Elizabeth] Evans, [1900] December 18; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Thanks her for example of "Filipino" workmanship; has not seen either Mr. Bass or Mr. Patterson. S.L.C.] (mourning stationery)
  - Mark Twain, New York, to Clarence F. Forrest, [1900] December 20; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Thanks him and "the Committee" for their invitation but is unable to accept. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1900 December 31; ALS, 4 p. (Box 5)
    Has received check from MacAlister; compliments him on business success; reports he is very busy with letters and speeches; says they are very lucky to have their large house; fumes about war in Philippines; encloses newspaper clipping (present). M.T.
  - Solon Robinson, Jamestown, TN, to Mark Twain with AN 1901 January 9 Mark Twain to Samuel E. [Moffett], ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Wishes to locate heirs of Dr. John Clemens, Jr., a nephew of Twain's father. In AN at bottom, Twain asks Samuel E. Moffett to respond if he wishes. S.L.C.
  - Franklin G. Whitmore, Hartford, CT, to Mark Twain with AN Mark Twain to Henry H. Rogers, 1901 January 9; TL, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Re Pratt & Whitney Company claim of debt owed for Paige Compositor Manufacturing Company; had supposed account had been closed; will check contract if Mark Twain would like; will send notices of Twain articles in North American Review if wanted; enclosing some letters. In AN to Henry H. Rogers, Twain says he sent Pratt & Whitney Company letter back to Pratt & Whitney; haven't heard from them.
  - Mark Twain, New York, to George A. Gates, 1901 January 21; TL (carbon copy), 1 p. (Box 5)
    Believes he is not able to answer part of Gates's speech and adds that the last paragraph of speech accurate picture of country. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, New York, to Sarah Holland Godfrey, Chicago, 1901 January 21; TL (carbon copy), 1 p. (Box 5)
    Says "The Alonzo Child" was the last steamboat he served on and that the boat later went into Confederate service; returned home on the "A.T. Lacey," missing the Memphis blockade by only a couple hours. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, New York, to Andrew Langdon, Buffalo, NY, 1901 January 21; TL (carbon copy), 1 p. (Box 5)
    Discusses a sculptor's name he does not recognize; sorry he missed Langdon's call; says Olivia and Clara are in D.C. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, New York, to J[ames] B. Pond, New York, 1901 January 21; TL (carbon copy), 1 p. (Box 5)
    About autographing volumes for Churchill. M.T.
  - Mark Twain, New York, to Robert N. Stanley, Highland Park, CT, 1901 January 21; TL (carbon copy), 1 p. (Box 5)
    Appreciates his pleasant words; believes things he has been saying are in the hearts of the nation's intelligent men but does not expect them to speak out publicly except when in the majority. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, New York, to W. T. Stead, London, 1901 January 21; TL (carbon copy), 1 p. (Box 5)
    Afraid Croker may not be dethroned; permits use of German chapter in his Annual but Stead will still need Chatto's permission. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, New York, to Ike Stern, Keokuk, IA, 1901 January 21; TL (carbon copy), 1 p. (Box 5)
    Regretfully declines invitation. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, New York, to E. T. Abbott, Duluth, MN, 1901 January 22; TL (carbon copy), 1 p. (Box 5)
    Thanks for newspaper clippings; remarks on advantage of knowing what the pulpit thinks of him. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, New York, to John T. Devine, Washington, DC, 1901 January 22; TL (carbon copy), 1 p. (Box 5)
    If they had heard from him in time, they would gladly have stayed with him. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, New York, to Edmund B. Kirby, Roseland, BC, 1901 January 22; TL (carbon copy), 1 p. (Box 5)
    Thanks for appreciation of his books and his expression of outspoken support and approval for Mark Twain's "Red Cross" blast. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, New York, to James W. Pryor, New York, 1901 January 22; TL (carbon copy), 1 p. (Box 5)
    Thanks for sending "those proofs" which he found instructive and entertaining. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, New York, to Mrs. Ira L. Smith, [1901 January]; TL (carbon copy), 1 p. (Box 5)
    The Library of Literature is wrong and Review of Reviews is correct that he was born in Florida, Missouri. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain to Franklin G. Whitmore, Hartford, CT, [1901 January.]; TL (carbon copy), 1 p. (Box 5)
    Re street sprinkling tax. Initialed
  - Mark Twain to Dr. [Channing H.] Cook, [1901] February 4; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Requests him to send several pounds of unspecified food to Katherine I. Harrison, who will eat part and distribute the rest to friends; will come soon. S.L.C.
  - L. B. Morgan, Pratt & Whitney Company, to Mark Twain, 1901 March 7; TLS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Requests that Twain pay debt for work done on Paige Compositor.
  - Franklin G. Whitmore to Mark Twain with AN on verso n.d. Mark Twain to Henry H. Rogers, 1901 March 9; TLS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Re Pratt & Whitney Company bill.
  - W. M. Storrs, Pratt & Whitney Company, to Henry H. Rogers, New York, 1901 March 13; TLS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Cover note for itemized bill of their account against Mark Twain
  - Mark Twain to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1901 March 24; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Giving note of introduction to Col. Harvey, president of Harper & Brothers; invited to cross by both Harvey and Rogers, with whom he would prefer to go, but cannot get away. S.L.C.] (w/env)
  - Mark Twain to R[ichard] U[nderwood] Johnson, New York, [1901 March 31]; APCS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Pleased with poem ["The White Man's Burden"]; thanks him for book; will be coming to consult "the bound Century." M.T.
  - W. M. Storrs, Pratt & Whitney Company, to Henry H. Rogers, New York, 1901 April 12; TLS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Encloses duplicate invoice re Mark Twain's outstanding account with Pratt & Whitney Company; with 2 duplicate invoices and worksheet detailing labor hours billed.
  - Mark Twain, New York, to Rudolf Lindau, 1901 April 24; TLS, 3 p. (Box 5)
    Says family, now in better health, enjoyed hearing from him; has not been working because of "too much speech-making"; has been criticizing American missionaries in China and is in trouble with the clergy and others; has been looking for summer house in Adirondacks; recounts anecdote about Emperor Wilhelm and Lindau; apologizes for dictating the letter but has too much correspondence to do otherwise. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1901 April 24; TLS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Suggests he visit America; discusses Plasmon's successes; glad that they were not bought out by the Plasmon Syndicate; wishes to be remembered to the Bergheims. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, New York, to Henry Stockbridge, Baltimore, 1901 April 24; TLS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Thanks him for sermon; will be meeting with a group of clergymen and says correspondent has supplied text for his talk: "the inability of the clerical profession to either quote correctly or even speak the truth off-hand." S.L.C.
  - W. M. Storrs, Pratt & Whitney Company, to Mark Twain, Hartford, CT, 1901 April 24; TLS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Re account settlement with Pratt & Whitney Company.
  - John E. Borne to Henry H. Rogers with TL copy, 1901 April 26; TLS, 9 p. (Box 5)
    Re interest charged to Charles L. Webster & Company by Mount Morris Bank by former bank managers. Enclosed copy (TL) of L. M. Schwan to John E. Borne re Webster business with Mount Morris Bank with copies of Webster accounts at the Mount Morris Bank.
  - L. B. Morgan, Pratt & Whitney Company, Hartford, CT, to Henry H. Rogers, New York, 1901 May 9; TLS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Re settlement for Mark Twain's account with Pratt & Whitney Company.
  - Urban H. Broughton, New York, to Katherine I. Harrison, New York, 1901 May 13; TLS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Re Mark Twain's account with Pratt & Whitney Company.
  - Franklin G. Whitmore, Hartford, CT, to Mark Twain, 1901 May 23; TLS, 4 p. (Box 5)
    Results of his research into Twain's Pratt & Whitney Company account and his recollections of the matter.
  - Mark Twain to Henry H. Rogers, [1901] June 3; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Cover note for business material. S.L.C.] (on 1/2 envelope [Franklin G.] Whitmore to Mark Twain )
  - Mark Twain, New York, to [Emma Beach] Thayer, [1901] June 5; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Has no desire to be president; sends regrets to her mother that they are unable to accept her invitation but they are packing for the summer move. S.L.C.
  - C. L. Cornell, Pratt & Whitney Company, Hartford, CT, to Mark Twain, 1901 June 17; TLS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Asks his personal attention to Pratt & Whitney Company claim.
  - Mark Twain to [Frank] Fuller, 1901 June 18; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Enjoyed his book, which took him back 50 years; encloses scheme for "drawing 'signed' ogres" (not present); thinks Aldrich may want to try it. S.L.C.
  - Clara Clemens to Samuel E. Moffett, 1901 July [23]; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Mark Twain will pay his share of the expenses of going to Tennessee and wishes him luck; enjoying stay in the mountains.] (w/mourning envelope) (mourning stationery)
  - Mark Twain to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1901 August 27; ALS, 4 p. (Box 5)
    Discusses Plasmon; mentions he is following Henry H. Rogers ' advice on other investments; has been writing for pleasure; refused offer to write for a magazine; has returned from yatching trip with Henry H. Rogers; is renting a large house in Ampersand; reports details of publishing contracts for new editions of his books. M.T.] (w/mourning env)
  - Mark Twain, Riverdale, NY, to Edmund Clarence Stedman, New York, 1901 October 8; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Says Mr. Dodge gave him a lift up the hill and promised to visit soon; hopes to have friendly neighbors because he and Olivia like company; will read Stedman's poem and hopes to see him soon. S.L.C.] (w/env)
  - Mark Twain, Riverdale, NY, to [William Webster] Ellsworth, [1901 October 15]; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Fascinated by project but decided against it because of possible misinterpretation. S.L.C.
  - Olivia L. Clemens, Riverdale, NY, to Will M. Clemens, [1901-1903 October]; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Thought her daughter had written him before; says Mark Twain is refusing requests for interviews because he feels everything of interest has been said about his life already.] (mourning stationery)
  - Mark Twain, Riverdale, NY, to Unknown, [1901-1903]; ANS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Requests that Clara's maid, bearer of this letter, be allowed to unpack Clara's trunk for her. M.T. and S.L.C.] (mourning stationery)
  - Mark Twain to Clara Clemens, [1902 January 1]; AL, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Asks if he should send a picture of "a picture of "a proud and haughty Russian" ( Ossip Gabrilowitsch ); hopes she will be well soon from measles; AN at bottom asks [Susan Crane] to read letter to Clara.
  - Mark Twain, Riverdale, NY, to [Elisabeth] Marbury, [1902] February 10; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Asks if she would help recover a ring from the theater at which "A Gentleman of France" matineed; says Olivia lost the ring there but got no response from the box office; was not able to get away to see her in person to make request. S.L.C.] (mourning stationery)
  - Mark Twain, Royal Poinciana, Palm Beach, FL, to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1902 March 17; ALS, 3 p. (Box 5)
    Discusses selling his Plasmon stock; named a director of the American Plasmon Company; setting off to meet Henry H. Rogers in Miami for West Indies cruise. M.T.] (w/env)
  - Mark Twain, Riverdale, NY, to [Robert Underwood] Johnson, 1902 April 14; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Comments nothing objectionable in unspecified forthcoming article; undecided on summer plans; if staying in America, will travel to Missouri to accept honorary degree from University of Missouri. S.L.C.] (mourning stationery)
  - Olivia L. Clemens, Riverdale, NY, to Unknown, 1902 April 24; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Mark Twain does not have old photographs to send per correspondent's request but is sending an autographed photograph and hopes it will do.
  - Mark Twain, York Harbor, ME, to Unknown, 1902 August 29; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Regrets he cannot accept invitation to speak but because of Olivia's precarious state of health he is not making out of town engagements; complains about the Postal system. S.L.C.] (mounted on card)
  - Mark Twain, York Harbor, ME, to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1902 September 6; ALS, 5 p. (Box 5)
    Hopes to move Olivia, who is now improving, to Elmira soon; wishes to be elected a Plasmon director at New York meeting in October.; sympathizes with him in his illness; offers remedy; relates how others took remedy only when he charged for it; "the human race is just a fool"; discusses his agreements with Harper's for articles and payment; has a finished article for Harper's which he send also to Lloyd's; if MacAlister does sell it to Lloyd's, please use the money to buy passage to America; will send it if Jean types it. M.T.] (w/env)
  - Mark Twain to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1902 September 23; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Asks he put aside "Amended Obituaries" for now; has withdrawn it from Harper's also; reports that Olivia gravely ill with heart disease. M.T.
  - Henry Wise, Banoctan, Union, P.I., to Mark Twain, 1902 October 6; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Apologizes for his presumption in his two previous letters; wishes to obtain a copy of Roughing It and would appreciate any help.
  - Mark Twain, New York City, to Edward W. Bok, 1902 October 18; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Wishes he could but is barred by existing contracts. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, Riverdale, NY, to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1902 October 18; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Gives permission to publish "Amended Obituaries" article; says Olivia is feeling much better; reports that her heart problem apparently disappeared but has nervous prostration; describes her condition and dependence on Clara and a trained nurse; adds that there will be a birthday banquet for him in New York in November. M.T.] (w/env)
  - Mark Twain, Riverdale, NY, to Magnus Gross, [1902] November 4; ALS (photocopy), 1 p. (Box 5)
    Declines invitation because he has too much work. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain to Edward W. Bok, 1902 November 22; LS,1 p. (Box 5)
    Bok may wait awhile since he is not considering breaking with Harper's but if he should be willing "to talk Christmas story" with Bok. S.L.C. in other hand
  - Mark Twain, Riverdale, NY, to Percy Spalding, 1902 December 15; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Discusses book he is writing on Christian Science; "chief writer of the cult" wants to write rejoinder and have it in book; Twain does not object; book will be out in end of March or mid April; request proofs from Harper & Brothers; says Olivia a little better. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain to Henry H. Rogers, post 1903 January 2; A Draft, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Draft for telegram re John T. Lewis's retirement; AN in corner says telegram not sent for lack of gravity. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain to [Herbert E.] Bowen, 1903 January 4; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Comments that the uncorrected proof sent him has cost him four hours work, three hours more than a corrected proof would have required; requests larger margins on proofs for corrections; will try to make report resemble a speech he has forgotten. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, Riverdale, NY, to Frank E. Bliss, post 1903 January 9; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Bliss can send advance; Henry H. Rogers says Bliss has nothing to fear from Harper & Brothers and that Bliss can come to him for help; Olivia and Jean doing well. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, Riverdale, NY, to unidentified recipient, [1903] January 14; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Responds to criticisms that his short story Was it heaven or hell? implied that lying was excusable under some circumstances by relating an incident in which his bedridden wife was not told about the critical illness of a daughter. The letter is accompanied by tear sheets of the story from Harpers Magazine and an obituary for Jean Clemens.
  - Mark Twain to [Frederick A. Duneka ], 1903 February; ANS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Fragment. Tells him to put in his conclusion to Christian Science.
  - Mark Twain to Secretary of the Plasmon Syndicate, [1903] April 7; ALS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Request to transfer half of his Plasmon Founders Shares to John Young Walker MacAlister. Witnessed and signed by Olivia L. Clemens. (Originally enclosed in ALS 1903 April 7 and May 8 Mark Twain to John Young Walker MacAlister ) S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, Riverdale, NY, to John Young Walker MacAlister, 1903 April 7 and May 8; ALS, 8 p. (Box 5)
    Glad to receive his letter; recounts how he mistakenly thought they had over-spent the family budget and what a shock this mistake gave him; reports Olivia is still very ill and is treated very delicately; plans to take her to Italy on doctors' orders; apologizes for not sending letter; has been very sick for a month; says he met with the Bergheims; is transferring shares to MacAlister; thanks him for past generosity; authorizations enclosed; reports on Henry H. Rogers, who has appendicitis; says Jean has measles and Olivia improving. M.T.] (w/env)
  - Peter Fenelon Collier Company to Mark Twain, 1903 May 28; TL, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Proposes to publish set of Mark Twain books from new plates with no restrictions on other editions of his books, save minimum price; offers royalty terms, a guaranteed payment, and option to buy back the plates.
  - [Mark Twain], Riverdale, NY, to Henry H. Rogers, 1903 June 25; ALS, 5 p. (Box 5)
    Discusses negotiations with American Publishing Company to market Hillcrest edition sets, disposal of old single editions, and Twain payment to American Publishing Company upon signing of contract; discusses negotiation with Collier's to sell sets by subscription and Harper & Brothers ' to sell to trade; mentions business discussion with Frederick A. Duneka; enjoyed visit with Rogers. "Billy's friend Dr. Rice"
  - Frank E. Bliss, Hartford, CT, to Mark Twain, 1903 June 27; TLS, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Discusses various proposals re sale of Hillcrest edition, uniform sets, agreements with Harper & Brothers and Mr. Collier, sale of plates to Twain, proposed Collier edition, contract with American Publishing Company and Olivia L. Clemens, royalties and other business matters.
  - F. N. Doubleday to Unknown, 1903 June 30; TD, 2 p. (Box 5)
    Report on Peter F. Collier and Robert J. Collier and their business; with autograph cover note from F. N. Doubleday; with Bradstreets "stamp" on back, addressed to Double & Page, August. 11, 1903.
  - Mark Twain, Elmira, NY, to Edward W. Bok, 1903 July 8; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Bok will need to come to Quarry Farm for photographs since he will be there for next six weeks. S.L.C.
  - Mark Twain, Elmira, NY, to Edward W. Bok, 1903 July 17; ALS, 1 p. (Box 5)
    Pictures of the Clemens' longtime summer house are finished; will sail for Italy in October; encloses brief explanations for the pictures (not present). S.L.C.